# 哈喽大家好，我是王刚
Hello everyone this is Wang Gang
# 本期视频我给大家分享一道
In today’s video I will share with you
# 家常版本的酸辣大白菜
how to make home styled sour and spicy Chinese cabbage
# 首先我们准备大白菜1颗
First, let’s prepare a Chinese cabbage
# 将叶子取下之后对半切开
cut it in half after peeling the leaves off
# 然后斜刀切成片备用
Then slant-cut into pieces
# 同学们切记不可用铁刀切白菜
Be sure not to use an iron knife
# 否则会有铁锈味
otherwise the cabbage might have a rusty taste
# 也可以用手将其撕成小片
you could also use your hands to rip it into pieces
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next step is to prepare the side ingredients
# 准备大蒜几颗拍散之后剁成蒜末备用
crush a few cloves of garlic and chop them up
# 准备干辣椒几颗剪成小节备用
cut a few dried chilli peppers into pieces
# 干辣椒的辣度各有不同
There are different levels of spiciness of dried peppers
# 可以根据个人口味和地方选择
you can make your own choice based on your preference
# 最后准备青红椒各半个切成片备用
Finally, prepare half of green and red peppers each and cut into pieces
# 加青红椒的目的是配色
The peppers make a good colour scheme for the dish
# 下一步开始调烹汁
The next step is to make the sauce
# 碗中加入食用盐1勺
add a spoonful of salt into a bowl
# 加入生抽酱油3克
add 3g of light soy sauce
# 加入香醋3克
and 3g "xiangcu" black vinegar
# 最后加入适量的水淀粉拌匀备用
lastly add some starch slurry
# 下一步开始制作
Now, let’s start cooking
# 首先我们把锅烧热
first, we heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的底油
add some oil once the wok is heated
# 油的量可以适量的多一点
we could add a bit more oil than usual
# 油温6成热之后加入准备好的蒜末和干辣椒爆香
Once the oil reaches about 180 degrees Celsius, add the garlic and dried chilli peppers and stir fry them
# 料头爆香之后加入切好的辣椒片和白菜
then put in the red and green peppers and the cabbage
# 然后转中大火爆炒40秒炒至断生
stir fry for 40 seconds on medium-high heat until slightly softened
# 同学们切记在保证白菜不糊的情况下尽量开大火
Make sure to set on high heat as long as the cabbage doesn't burn
# 否则小火慢炒白菜会容易出水
otherwise the cabbage might become soggy
# 大火爆炒40秒之后加入调好的料汁
Stir fry on high heat for 40 seconds then add the sauce
# 然后将其翻炒均匀
stir fry and mix them well
# 最后在起锅之前加入适量的明油即可出锅装盘
lastly add some oil and quick-fry for a few seconds, the dish is ready to serve
# 一道口味酸辣爽口的大白菜就制作完成
a tasty dish of sour and spicy cabbage is now finished
# 下面开始技术总结
Here is a summary for the tips
# 第一，爆炒白菜不能停火慢慢调味，必须实现兑料汁
first, you cannot lower the heat and add seasoning during the cooking process, making the sauce beforehand is necessary.
# 第二，炒白菜必须大火爆炒，可以多加油防止炒糊
second, high heat is needed for stir-frying cabbage, you can add some more oil to prevent overcooking the cabbage.
# 第三，此菜必须最后放盐或者烹料汁，提前调味会导致白菜出水不香
Third, sauce or salt must be added towards the end. The cabbage will become soggy and less tasty if you add the sauce early
# 酸辣大白菜的技术总结完毕
That’s all for the tips.